Do you ever look
at someone and wonder...
"What is going on inside their head?"
Well, I know. Well, I know Riley's head.
And there she was...
Hello.
Riley.
Look at you.
Aren't you a little bundle of joy?
It was amazing.
Just Riley and me. Forever.
For 33 seconds.
I'm Sadness.
Hello. I... I'm Joy. So...
Can I just... If you could...
I just want to fix that. Thanks.
And that was just the beginning.
Headquarters only got
more crowded from there.
Very nice. Okay, looks like
you got this. Very good.
Sharp turn! No! Look out! No!
That's Fear.
He's really good at keeping Riley safe.
Easy, easy. We're good. We're good.
- Good job.
- Thank you. Thank you very much.
And we're back!
Here we go. All right, open.
- This looks new.
- You think it's safe?
What is it?
Okay, caution.
There is a dangerous smell, people.
Hold on. What is that?
This is Disgust.
She basically keeps
Riley from being poisoned.
Physically and socially
That is not brightly colored
or shaped like a dinosaur.
Hold on, guys.
It's broccoli!
Yucky!
Well, I just saved our lives.
Yeah. You're welcome.
Riley, if you don't eat your dinner,
you're not gonna get any dessert.
Wait. Did he just say
we couldn't have dessert?
That's Anger.
He cares very deeply
about things being fair.
So that's how you want to play it,
old man? No dessert?
Sure, we'll eat our dinner!
Right after you eat this!
Riley, Riley, here comes an airplane!
Airplane. We got an airplane, everybody.
Airplane.
And you've met Sadness.
She... Well, she...
I'm not actually sure what she does.
And I've checked,
there's no place for her to go, so...
She's good, we're good. It's all great!
Anyway, these are Riley's memories
and they're mostly happy,
you'll notice. Not to brag.
But the really important ones
are over here.
I don't want to get too technical,
but these are called Core Memories.
Each one came from
a super important time in Riley's life.
Like when she first scored a goal.
That was so amazing!
Hey! Would you look at that? Very nice!
- We got a future center here!
- Nice job.
And each Core Memory
powers a different aspect
of Riley's personality.
Like Hockey Island.
Goofball Island is my personal favorite.
Come back here, you little monkey!
You're silly.
Yep, Goofball is the best.
Friendship Island is pretty good too.
I love Honesty Island.
And that's the truth!
And of course, Family Island is amazing.
The point is, the Islands of Personality
are what make Riley... Riley!
Look out, mermaid!
Lava!
Who's your friend who likes to play?
Bing Bong, Bing Bong!
- Hey! Very nice!
- Where'd you learn that?
Brain freeze!
Yeah!
- Good night, kiddo.
- Good night, Dad.
And... we're out!
That's what I'm talking about!
Another perfect day!
Nice job, everybody!
Let's get those memories
down to Long Term.
All right, we did not die today!
I call that an unqualified success.
And that's it. We love our girl.
She's got great friends
and a great house.
Things couldn't be better.
After all, Riley's 11 now.
What could happen?
What...
Okay, not what I had in mind.
Hey, look! The Golden Gate Bridge!
Isn't that great?
It's not made out of
solid gold like we thought,
which is kind of
a disappointment, but still...
I sure am glad you told me
earthquakes are a myth, Joy.
Otherwise I'd be terrified right now!
Yeah...
- Are you kidding? Get out of the street!
- For Pete's sake! Move it!
These are my kind of people.
All right, just a few more blocks.
We're almost to our new house!
Step on it, Daddy!
Why don't we just
live in this smelly car?
We've already been in it forever.
Which, actually, was really lucky,
because that gave us
plenty of time to think about
what our new house
is going to look like!
What! Let's review
the top five daydreams.
- That looks safe!
- That one's nice.
This will be great for Riley!
No, no, no, no, this one!
Joy, for the last time,
she cannot live in a cookie.
That's the one! It comes with a dragon.
Now we're getting close, I can feel it.
Here it is, here's our new house. And...
Maybe it's nice on the inside.
- We're supposed to live here?
- Do we have to?
I'm telling you, it smells like
something died in here.
Can you die from moving?
Guys, you're overreacting.
Nobody is dying...
A dead mouse!
- Great. This is just great.
- I'm gonna be sick.
It's the house of the dead!
We're going to get rabies!
Get off of me!
Hey. All through the drive,
Dad talked about
how cool our new room is.
Let's go check it out!
- Let's go!
- It's gonna be great!
Yes, yes, yes.
No, no, no, no, no.
I'm starting to envy the dead mouse.
Get out the rubber ball,
we're in solitary confinement.
Riley can't live here.
- She's right.
- It's the worst.
- Really bad.
- It's absolutely the worst.
It's the worst place
I've ever been in my entire life.
Hey, it's nothing
our butterfly curtains couldn't fix.
I read somewhere
that an empty room is an opportunity.
Where did you read that?
It doesn't matter.
I read it and it's great.
We'll put the bed there.
And the desk over there.
- The hockey lamp goes there.
- Put the chair there.
- The trophy collection goes there.
- Stars! I like that!
Now we're talking! Let's go
get our stuff from the moving van!
All right. Goodbye.
Well, guess what? The moving van
won't be here until Thursday.
You're kidding.
The van is lost?
It is the worst day ever!
That figures. The van is lost.
You said it would be here yesterday!
I know that's what I said.
That's what they told me!
Mom and Dad are stressed out!
- They're stressed out?
- What are we going to do?
I've got a great idea!
Did you even read the contract?
Andersen makes her move.
She's closing in!
Hey!
No, you're not!
She's lining up for the shot!
Coming behind you.
- Watch out! Watch out!
- She shoots and she scores! Yeah!
Come on, Grandma!
"Grandma"?
She put her hair up, we're in for it!
Hey, put me down!
Sorry. Hold on. Hold on.
Hello?
Wait. Wh...
You're kidding.
All right. Stall for me.
I'll be right there.
The investor's supposed to show up
on Thursday, not today!
- I got to go.
- It's okay. We get it.
You're the best. Thanks, hon.
See you, sweetie.
Dad just left us.
He doesn't love us anymore. That's sad.
I should drive, right?
Joy? What are you doing?
Just give me one second.
You know what I've realized?
Riley hasn't had lunch! Remember?
Hey, I saw a pizza place
down the street.
Maybe we could try that?
Pizza sounds delicious.
- Pizza? That's good.
- Yes! Pizza!
- What the heck is that?
- Who puts broccoli on pizza?
That's it. I'm done.
Congratulations, San Francisco,
you've ruined pizza!
First the Hawaiians and now you!
What kind of a pizza place
only serves one kind of pizza?
Must be a San Francisco thing, huh?
Still, it's not as bad as that soup.
At that diner in Nebraska.
Yeah. The spoon stood up
in the soup by itself!
That was disgusting.
Good. Family is running.
Dad's got a steel stomach.
The drive out was pretty fun, huh?
What was your favorite part?
Spitting out the car window!
Definitely not when Dad was singing.
Wearing a seat belt!
What about the time with the dinosaur?
- That's the one.
- Definitely!
Say cheese!
- Dad! Dad!
- Honey!
- Now hold still.
- The car!
Stop! No, no, no!
Nice one, Joy.
I liked that time at the dinosaur.
That was pretty funny.
Wait. What? What happened?
She did something to the memory.
What did you do?
I just touched it.
- That shouldn't make it change.
- Change it back, Joy!
- I'm trying.
- You can't change it back?
- No! I guess I can't!
- Good going, Sadness.
Now when Riley thinks of that moment
with Dad, she's gonna feel sad. Bravo.
I'm sorry, Joy. I don't really know...
I thought maybe if you...
Joy, we've got a stairway coming up.
Just don't touch any other memories
until we figure out what's going on.
- Okay.
- All right. Get ready.
This is a monster railing
and we are riding it all the way down!
Wait, what? What happened?
- A Core Memory!
- No!
Sadness, what are you doing?
It looked like one was crooked
so I opened it and then it fell out. I...
It's just that...
I wanted to maybe hold one.
- Joy!
- Whoa, whoa.
Sadness, you nearly
touched a Core Memory.
And when you touch them,
we can't change them back.
I know. I'm sorry.
Something's wrong with me.
It's like I'm having a breakdown.
You're not having a breakdown.
It's stress.
I keep making mistakes like that.
I'm awful.
- No, you're not.
- And annoying.
You know what?
You can't focus on what's going wrong.
There's always a way to
turn things around, to find the fun.
Yeah. Find the fun.
I don't know how to do that.
Okay. Well, try to think
of something funny.
Remember the funny movie
where the dog dies?
Yeah, that's not...
What about that time with Meg
when Riley laughed so hard
milk came out of her nose?
Yeah. That hurt. It felt like fire.
It was awful.
Okay, okay, don't think of that.
Let's try something else.
What are your favorite things to do?
My favorite?
Well, I like it when we're outside.
That's good.
Like there's the beach and sunshine.
Like that time we buried Dad
in the sand up to his neck.
I was thinking more like rain.
Rain? Rain is my favorite, too!
We can stomp around in puddles.
You know, there's cool umbrellas,
lightning storms.
More like when the rain runs down
our back and makes our shoes soggy.
And we get all cold, shivery,
and everything just
starts feeling droopy.
Hey, hey. Hey, easy.
Why are you crying?
It's just like really the opposite
of what we're going for here.
Crying helps me slow down and obsess
over the weight of life's problems.
You know what?
Let's, think about something else.
How about we read some
mind manuals, huh? Sounds fun.
I've read most of them.
Well, have you read this one?
This seems interesting.
"Long Term Memory Retrieval, Volume 47"?
- No.
- A real page-turner!
"Long Term Memory data selection
via channel subgrouping"?
See? Fun already! You lucky dog.
You're reading these cool things.
I got to go work. Life is so unfair.
What can we do? We've only got capital
to last a month, maybe two.
If we can't find investors by then,
we're going to have to lay people off.
Mom! Dad! Come kiss me good night!
- I know. I know.
- Be right there!
We've got to land this, okay?
Did you hear Dad?
He sounded really upset.
What was that?
Was it a bear? It's a bear!
There are no bears in San Francisco.
I saw a really hairy guy.
He looked like a bear.
I'm so jumpy. My nerves are shot.
I don't want to hear about your nerves.
I'll tell you what it is.
This move has been a bust.
That's what I've been telling you guys!
There are at least 37 things
for Riley to be scared of right now.
The smell alone
is enough to make her gag.
I can't believe
Mom and Dad moved us here!
Look, I get it. You guys have concerns.
But we've been through worse!
Tell you what, let's make a list
of all the things
Riley should be happy about.
Fine. Let's see, this house stinks,
our room stinks.
- Pizza is weird here.
- Our friends are back home.
And all of our stuff
is in the missing van!
Come on. It could be worse.
Yeah, Joy. We could be lying
on the dirty floor. In a bag.
Okay, I admit it, we had a rough start.
But think of all the good things that...
No, Joy. There's absolutely no reason
for Riley to be happy right now.
Let us handle this.
I say we skip school tomorrow
and lock ourselves in the bedroom.
We have no clean clothes.
I mean, no one should see us.
Yeah, we could cry
until we can't breathe.
We should lock the door
and scream that curse word we know.
- It's a good one!
- Now hold on!
Look, we all have our off days.
You know...
Hi, honey.
The Mom bad news train is pulling in.
Toot-toot!
Still no moving van.
Now they're saying it won't be here
till Tuesday, can you believe it?
Toot-toot-toot!
Where's Dad?
On the phone. This new venture
is keeping him pretty busy.
I rest my case!
Your dad's a little stressed,
you know, about getting
his new company up and running.
Now for a few
well-placed withering scowls.
I guess all I really want to say is,
thank you.
You know, through all this confusion
you've stayed...
Well, you've stayed our happy girl.
Your dad's under a lot of pressure,
but if you and I can keep smiling,
it would be a big help.
We can do that for him. Right?
Well.
Yeah, sure.
What did we do to deserve you?
- Sweet dreams.
- Good night.
Well, you can't argue with Mom.
Happy it is.
Team Happy! Sounds great!
Totally behind you, Joy.
Looks like we're going into REM.
I got Dream Duty, so I'll take care
of sending these to Long Term.
Great day today, guys!
Sleep well, Team Happy!
All right, what's on tonight,
Dream Production?
Well, this is it. The new place.
Come live with me, Riley.
Somebody order a broccoli pizza?
- Eat me!
- I'm organic!
No! Who is in charge
of programing down there?
I know I'm not supposed
to do this, but...
We are not going to
end the day like this.
Don't you worry.
I'm gonna make sure
that tomorrow is another great day.
I promise.
Hello! Did I wake you?
Do you have to play that?
Well, I have to practice.
And I don't think of it as playing
so much as hugging.
Okay, first day of school!
Very, very exciting.
I was up late last night
figuring out a new plan.
Here it is! Fear.
I need a list of all the possible
negative outcomes
on the first day at a new school.
Way ahead of you there. Does anyone
know how to spell "meteor"?
Disgust. Make sure Riley stands out
today. But also blends in.
When I'm through,
Riley will look so good,
the other kids will
look at their own outfits and barf.
"Joy." "Yes, Joy?"
"You'll be in charge of the console,
keeping Riley happy all day long.
"And may I add I love your dress?
It's adorable."
"This old thing? Thank you so much.
I love the way it twirls."
Train of Thought! Right on schedule.
Anger. Unload the daydreams.
I ordered extra
in case things get slow in class.
It might come in handy.
If this new school is
full of boring, useless classes.
Which it probably will be.
Sadness. I have a
super important job just for you.
- Really?
- Follow me.
- What are you doing?
- And there. Perfect!
This is the circle of Sadness.
Your job is to make sure that
all the Sadness stays inside of it.
So you want me to just stand here?
Hey, it's not my place
to tell you how to do your job.
Just make sure that
all the Sadness stays in the circle!
See? You're a pro at this!
Isn't this fun?
- No.
- Atta girl.
All right, everyone, fresh start.
We are gonna have a good day,
which will turn into a good week,
which will turn into a good year,
which turns into a good life!
So, the big day!
New school, new friends, huh?
I know! I'm kind of nervous,
but I'm mostly excited.
How do I look? Do you like my shirt?
Very cute!
Are you gonna be okay?
You want us to walk with you?
Mom and Dad? With us in public?
- No thank you.
- I'm on it!
Nope! I'm fine. Bye, Mom. Bye, Dad.
Have a good day at school, monkey.
Have a great day, sweetheart!
- That's crazy. It really is.
- That was so funny.
Do you know what
basketball game is coming up?
Are you sure we want to do this?
- In we go!
- Okay! Going in! Yes!
Did you see her? Hello!
Okay, we've got a group
of cool girls at two o'clock.
- How do you know?
- Double ears pierced, infinity scarf.
Is she wearing eye shadow?
- Yeah, we want to be friends with them.
- Let's go talk to them!
Are you kidding?
We're not talking to them.
We want them to like us.
Yeah. Wait, what?
Almost finished
with the potential disasters.
Worst scenario is either quicksand,
spontaneous combustion,
or getting called on by the teacher.
So as long as none of those happen...
Okay, everybody.
We have a new student in class today.
Are you kidding me? Out of the gate?
This is not happening!
Riley, would you like to tell us
something about yourself?
No! Pretend we can't speak English.
Don't worry. I got this.
Okay.
My name is Riley Andersen.
I'm from Minnesota and now I live here.
And how about Minnesota?
Can you tell us something about it?
Well, you certainly
get a lot more snow than we do.
She's hilarious!
Yeah, it gets pretty cold.
The lake freezes over,
and that's when we play hockey.
I'm on a great team.
We're called the Prairie Dogs.
My friend Meg plays forward.
And my dad's the coach.
Pretty much everyone
in my family skates.
It's kind of a family tradition.
We go out on the lake
almost every weekend.
Or we did, till I moved away.
- Hey, what gives?
- Wait, what?
Hey, Sadness! You touched a memory?
We talked about this.
Yeah, I know. I'm sorry.
Get back in your circle.
- What's going on? Why won't it eject?
- Get it out of there, Joy.
We used to play tag and stuff.
Cool kids whispering at three o'clock!
- Did you see that look?
- No.
They're judging us!
Somebody help me!
Grab that... Everybody put...
But everything's different now.
Since we moved.
No! We're crying! At school!
What? Sadness! What are you doing?
Oh, no! I'm sorry!
It's a Core Memory!
But it's blue.
No! Wait! Stop it! No! No!
Joy, no.
- That's a Core Memory!
- Hey!
- Joy, wait!
- Stop it! Let go!
The Core Memories!
No, no, no, no!
Thank you, Riley.
I know it can be tough
moving to a new place,
but we're happy to have you here.
All right, everyone,
get out your history books
and turn to chapter seven.
Can I say that curse word now?
No! One, two, three. Okay.
I got them. Where are we?
Long Term Memory? Wait...
Goofball Island?
Riley's Islands of Personality.
They're all down!
This is bad.
We... We can fix this!
We just have to get back
to Headquarters,
plug the Core Memories in,
and Riley will be back to normal.
Riley has no Core Memories.
No Personality Islands and no...
What? What is it?
You.
You're not in Headquarters.
Without you, Riley can't be happy.
We got to get you back up there.
I'm coming, Riley.
So, as it turns out, the green trash can
is not recycling, it's for greens.
Like compost. And eggshells.
And the blue one is recycling.
And the black one is trash.
Riley is acting so weird.
Why is she acting so weird?
What do you expect?
All the Islands are down.
Joy would know what to do.
That's it.
Until she gets back,
we just do what Joy would do!
Great idea. Anger, Fear, Disgust,
how are we supposed to be happy?
Hey, Riley. I've got good news!
I found a junior hockey league
right here in San Francisco.
And get this: try-outs are tomorrow
after school. What luck, right?
- Hockey?
- What do we do?
Guys, this is...
You pretend to be Joy.
Won't it be great
to be back out on the ice?
Yeah, that sounds fantastic.
What was that?
That wasn't anything like Joy!
- Because I'm not Joy.
- Yeah, no kidding.
Did you guys pick up on that?
- Something's wrong.
- Totally.
Should we ask her?
Let's probe. But keep it subtle,
so she doesn't notice.
So, how was the first day of school?
She's probing us.
I'm done. You pretend to be Joy.
What? Okay.
It was fine, I guess. I don't know.
Very smooth. That was just like Joy.
Something is definitely going on.
She's never acted like this before.
What should we do?
We're going to find out
what's happening.
But we'll need support.
Signal the husband.
With a nice pass over to Reeves,
comes across... and nice!
She's looking at us.
- What did she say?
- What?
Sorry, sir. No one was listening.
Is it garbage night?
We left the toilet seat up?
What? What is it, woman? What?
He's making that stupid face again.
I could strangle him right now.
Signal him again.
So, Riley, how was school?
- You got to be kidding me!
- Seriously?
For this we gave up
that Brazilian helicopter pilot?
Move! I'll be Joy.
School was great, all right?
Riley. Is everything okay?
Sir, she just rolled her eyes at us.
What is her deal?
All right, make a show of force.
I don't want to have to
put "the foot" down.
No, not the foot!
Riley, I do not like this new attitude.
I'll show you attitude, old man.
No. No, no, no! Stay happy!
What is your problem?
Just leave me alone!
Sir, reporting high levels of sass!
Take it to DEFCON Two.
You heard that, gentlemen. DEFCON Two.
Listen, young lady, I don't know where
this disrespectful attitude came from...
You want a piece of this, pops?
Come and get it!
Yeah, well... Well...
Here it comes. Prepare the foot!
Keys to safety position.
Ready to launch on your command, sir!
Just shut up!
Fire!
That's it! Go to your room! Now!
The foot is down! The foot is down!
Good job, gentlemen.
That could have been a disaster.
Well, that was a disaster.
Come fly with me, gatinha.
We're going to walk out there? On that?
It's the quickest way back.
But it's right over the Memory Dump.
If we fall, we'll be forgotten forever.
We have to do this for Riley.
Just follow my footsteps.
- Okay.
- It's not that high. It's totally fine...
Hey.
So, things got
a little out of hand downstairs.
Do you want to talk about it?
Come on, where's my happy girl?
Monkey.
He's trying to start up Goofball.
Come on!
Go back! Run, run, run!
What...
I get it. You need some alone time.
We'll talk later.
We have a major problem.
Joy, where are you?
We lost Goofball Island.
That means she can lose Friendship
and Hockey and Honesty and Family.
You can fix this, right, Joy?
I...
I don't know.
But we have to try. Okay, come on.
Riley's gone to sleep.
Which is a good thing.
When you think about it because
nothing else bad can happen
while she's asleep.
We'll be back to Headquarters
before she wakes up.
We'll just go across Friendship Island.
We'll never make it.
- No!
- No, no, no!
Don't obsess over
the weight of life's problems.
Remember the funny movie
where the dog dies?
Sadness, we don't have time for this.
We'll just have to go around.
Take the scenic route.
Wait, Joy, you could get lost in there!
Think positive!
Okay. I'm positive
you will get lost in there.
That's Long Term Memory.
An endless warren
of corridors and shelves.
I read about it in the manuals.
The manuals? The manuals!
- You read the manuals!
- Yeah.
So you know the way
back to Headquarters!
I guess.
You are my map!
Let's go! Lead on, my map!
Show me where we're going!
Okay. Only I'm too sad to walk.
Just give me a few... hours.
Which way? Left?
Right.
No. I mean, go left.
I said left was right. Like "correct."
Okay.
This actually feels kind of nice.
Okay, here we go! We'll be back
to Headquarters before morning.
We can do it! This will be easy!
This is working!
This is not working.
Are we getting close?
Yeah, just another right.
And... a left and then another...
left and...
Are you sure you know where we're going?
Because we seem to be
walking away from Headquarters.
Riley's awake.
Don't touch. Remember?
If you touch them, they stay sad.
Sorry, I won't. Starting now.
I can't take much more of this.
Forget them!
- Mind workers!
- But, Joy, we're almost...
Phone numbers. We don't need
all these. They're in her phone.
- Excuse me, hi.
- Just forget all of that. Please. Forget it!
- I need to find Friendship Island.
- Look at this.
Four years of piano lessons.
Yeah, it looks pretty faded.
You know what? Save Chopsticks
and Heart and Soul, get rid of the rest.
- Are you...
- U.S. Presidents. What do you think?
Yeah, just keep Washington,
Lincoln and the fat one.
- Forget them!
- Hey! You can't throw those away!
Those are perfectly good memories.
The names of
every "Cutie Pie Princess" doll?
Yes! That is critical information!
Glitterstorm, Honeypants...
Forget them!
Hey! Bring those back!
They're in the dump.
Nothing comes back from the dump.
Yeah. Look, lady, this is our job, okay?
When Riley doesn't care
about a memory, it fades.
- Fades?
- Happens to the best of them.
Yeah, except for this bad boy.
This one will never fade.
- TripleDent gum
- Will make you smile
The song from the gum commercial?
You know, sometimes we send that one
up to Headquarters for no reason.
It just plays in Riley's head
over and over again.
Like a million times!
Let's watch it again!
TripleDent gum
Yeah, I know. We all know the song.
Okay. Yeah, real catchy. Okay.
Hey, what do you think? Should we do it?
Yeah!
Okay, here we go!
TripleDent gum
What the... This again?
Wait! Do you know
how to get to Friendship Island?
TripleDent gum
Do you like it there? Did you feel
any earthquakes? Is the bridge cool?
Yeah, it's good.
What happened with the playoffs?
We won the first game.
Coach says we might actually
go to the finals this year.
And we've got this new girl
on the team. She's so cool.
She did not just say that.
A new girl?
Meg has a new friend already?
Hey, hey! Stay happy!
We do not want to lose
any more islands here, guys!
We can pass the puck to each other
without even looking.
It's like mind reading!
You like to read minds, Meg?
I got something for you to read,
right here!
Let's just be calm for one second!
- I heard they have parrots...
- I've got to go.
- What?
- I got to go!
Okay, could you just please
tell me which way is... Oh, no!
Friendship Island! What?
Not Friendship.
Riley loved that one. And now it's gone.
Goodbye, friendship. Hello, loneliness.
We'll just have to go the long way.
Yeah. The long, long, long, long way.
I'm ready.
There's got to be a better way.
Look at you!
I will take you, but not you.
Who am I kidding? I can't leave you.
Hello!
Wait! Hey! Wait!
Wait! Stop!
Excuse me.
I was looking for... Diversion!
- What?
- So long, sucker!
I hurt all over.
Wait. I know you.
No, you don't. I get that a lot.
I look like a lot of people.
No, no, no. I do.
Bing Bong! Riley's imaginary friend!
- You really do know me?
- Well, of course!
Riley loved playing with you!
You two are best friends!
You would know. We're trying
to get back to Headquarters.
Headquarters?
You guys are from Headquarters?
Well, yeah. I'm Joy. This is Sadness.
You're Joy? The Joy?
What the heck are you doing out here?
That's a good question.
You want to answer that, Sadness?
Without you, Riley won't ever be happy.
We can't have that.
We got to get you back.
I'll tell you what. Follow me!
Thank you!
It is so great to see you again.
I gotta tell you,
I am such a huge fan of your work.
Do you remember
when you and Riley were in a band?
I went to all of your concerts.
Yeah, I blow a mean nose.
Watching you play tag was such a treat.
Two-time world champ.
And remember your rockets?
Of course! It runs on song power!
That's right! Your theme song!
Who's your friend who likes to play?
Bing Bong
His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"
- Bing Bong, Bing Bong
What exactly are you supposed to be?
You know, it's unclear.
I'm mostly cotton candy.
But shape-wise I'm part cat,
part elephant, part dolphin.
Dolphin?
You got to remember, when Riley
was three, animals were all the rage.
The cow goes moo. The horse goes neigh.
That's all people
talked about back then.
Yeah. Yeah. I guess that's true.
What are you doing out here?
Well, there's not much call
for imaginary friends lately.
So I, you know...
Hey, hey. Don't be sad.
Tell you what.
When I get back up to Headquarters,
I'll make sure Riley remembers you.
- You will?
- Of course! She'd love that.
This is the greatest day of my life!
Are you okay?
- Hey, what's going on?
- I cry candy.
Try the caramel. It's delicious.
- Here, use this.
- Thanks!
Hold on, wait a second.
It always gets stuck at the bottom.
Here. What? It's imaginary.
Thanks. This will make it a lot easier
to walk back to Headquarters.
Walk? We're not walking.
We're taking the Train of Thought!
The train, of course!
That is so much faster!
But how do we catch it?
Well, it kind of goes
all over the place,
but there is a station
in Imagination Land.
I know a shortcut. Come on, this way!
I am so glad we ran into you!
The station is right through here.
After you.
- Joy.
- What?
I read about this place in the manual.
We shouldn't go in there.
Bing Bong says
it's the quickest way to Headquarters.
No, but, Joy, this is abstract thought.
What are you talking about? I go in here
all the time. It's a shortcut, you see?
D-A-N-G-E-R. Shortcut.
I'll prove it to you.
Look at me. I'm closer to the station
because I'm taking the shortcut.
Let's go around. This way.
Almost there!
If you want to walk the long way,
go for it.
But Riley needs to be happy.
I'm not missing that train.
Bing Bong knows what he's doing.
He's part dolphin. They're very smart.
Well, I guess.
- What did you get?
- I don't know.
Okay, what abstract concept
are we trying to comprehend today?
Loneliness.
Looks like there's something in there.
I'm going to turn it on for a minute
and burn out the gunk.
What did I tell you?
You'll be at Headquarters in no time.
Say, would you look at that?
- What's happening?
- Oh, no, they turned it on.
Never seen this before.
My face! My beautiful face!
- What is going on?
- We're abstracting!
There are four stages. This is the first:
Non-objective Fragmentation!
All right. Do not panic.
What is important
is that we all stay together.
We're in the second stage.
We're deconstructing!
Run!
I can't feel my legs!
There they are.
Come here, me!
We've got to get out of here before
we're nothing but shape and color!
We'll get stuck here forever!
Stuck? Why did we come in here?
I told you, it's a shortcut!
The train!
Oh, no. We're two-dimensional!
That's stage three!
We're getting nowhere!
- Depth! I'm lacking depth!
- Come on.
We can't fit.
Oh, no, we're Nonfigurative.
This is the last stage!
We're not going to make it!
Wait! We're two-dimensional.
Fall on your face!
Stop! Stop!
No! I thought you said
that was a shortcut.
I did, but wow,
we should not have gone in there.
That was dangerous!
They really should put up a sign.
How long until the next train?
Who knows. But don't worry.
There's another station. That way.
The train always stops there.
Right before it goes to Headquarters.
If we hurry, we can catch it.
This isn't another one
of your shortcuts, is it?
Yeah!
Is there really another station?
Through there.
Welcome to Imagination Land!
- Imagination Land?
- Sure!
I come here all the time.
I'm practically the mayor.
Hey, you guys hungry?
There's French Fry Forest!
- Delicious.
- No way!
Check it out! Trophy Town!
Medals! Ribbons! Everyone's a winner!
I won first place!
- Me too!
- Participation award.
Wait, is that...
Sadness, look, it's Cloud Town!
That is my favorite!
It's so soft!
Let me try.
Hey! What's the big idea?
You better fix that wall,
or else you're in big troub...
Oh, no! Lava!
Imagination Land is the best!
Is it all going to be so interactive?
Hey, look! The House of Cards!
Wait. Hang on just a minute.
- Your rocket!
- Yeah.
I stashed it in there for safekeeping,
and now I'm all set to
take Riley to the moon!
- I'm sorry.
- Great.
I love Imagination Land.
Isn't it great? And there's
always something new, like...
Who the heck is that?
Imaginary boyfriend.
I would die for Riley.
- I've never seen him before.
- I live in Canada.
Anyway, this way.
Through Preschool World!
- We're nearly to the train!
- Riley, here we come!
This should be fun!
New team, new friends.
These kids look pretty good,
considering they're from San Francisco.
Okay, Andersen, you're up!
- Got to go.
- Okay. Good luck, sweetie!
Luck isn't going to help us now.
If she tries to use Hockey Island,
it's going down.
Which is why I've recalled
every hockey memory I can think of.
One of these has got to work
in place of the Core Memory.
- She's about to play!
- Hurry!
We did it, gang! It's working!
Line change! Line change! Change it up!
No! No!
It's like we don't learn anything.
- Come on!
- Let's pick it up out there!
Pass! Shoot it! Shoot it!
- That's it!
- No, no, no! Breathe.
Find your happy place.
What's her problem?
- Riley. What's wrong?
- Let's go.
- You're not going to finish try-outs?
- What's the point?
Hey. It'll be all right.
Let's just go back...
Stop saying everything
will be all right!
Nice hustle, ladies!
Hockey?
No, no, she loves hockey.
She can't give up hockey.
- Hey! Look at that! Very nice shot!
- Hey!
Bing Bong,
we have to get to that station.
Sure thing. This way,
just past Graham Cracker Castle.
Hey. That's weird. Graham Cracker
Castle used to be right here.
I wonder why they moved it?
That's not...
I would have sworn
Sparkle Pony Mountain was right here.
- Hey, what's going on?
- Yeah, yeah... I don't know...
- We'll have to come back.
- Princess Dream World!
Oh, no! The stuffed Animal Hall of Fame!
My rocket!
Wait! Riley and I,
we're still using that rocket!
It still has some song power left!
Who's your friend who likes to play?
No! No, no, no. No, you can't
take my rocket to the dump!
Riley and I are going to the moon!
Riley can't be done with me.
Hey, it's going to be okay!
We can fix this!
We just need to
get back to Headquarters.
Which way to the train station?
I had a whole trip planned for us.
Hey, who's ticklish, huh?
Here comes the tickle monster!
Hey, Bing Bong! Look at this!
Here's a fun game!
You point to the train station
and we all go there!
Won't that be fun?
Come on, let's go to the train station!
I'm sorry they took your rocket.
They took something that you loved.
It's gone. Forever.
Sadness. Don't make him feel worse.
- Sorry.
- It's all I had left of Riley.
I bet you and Riley
had great adventures.
They were wonderful.
Once we flew back in time.
We had breakfast twice that day.
Sadness...
It sounds amazing. I bet Riley liked it.
She did. We were best friends.
Yeah. It's sad.
I'm okay now.
Come on. The train station is this way.
How did you do that?
I don't know. He was sad.
So I listened to what...
Hey! There's the train!
We made it!
We're finally going to get home!
Oh, no! These Facts and Opinions
look so similar.
Don't worry about it.
Happens all the time.
On a scale of one to ten,
I give this day an F.
Well, why don't we quit standing around
and do something?
Like what, genius?
Like quitting. That's what I'm doing.
Sure it's the coward's way out.
But this coward's gonna survive.
Emotions can't quit, genius!
I thought we were supposed
to be keeping Riley happy.
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
- What is it?
- Nothing.
- Just the best idea ever.
- What?
All the good Core Memories
were made in Minnesota.
Ergo, we go
back to Minnesota and make more.
- Ta-da!
- Wait, wait, wait.
You're saying we run away?
Well, I wouldn't call it that.
I'd call it the Happy Core
Memory Development program.
You can't be serious.
Hey! Our life was perfect
until Mom and Dad decided
to move to San Fran Stinktown.
I mean, it's just so drastic!
Need I remind you
of how great things were there?
Our room? Our back yard? Our friends?
- TripleDent gum
- Will make you smile
Did I ask for the gum commercial?
Anyway, it was better, that's my point.
Yeah, Riley was happier in Minnesota.
Wait. Hold on. Shouldn't we
just sleep on this or something?
Fine. Let's sleep on it.
Because, hey,
I'm sure jolly fun-filled times
are just around the corner.
Hey, hey! Why aren't we moving?
Riley's gone to sleep.
We're all on break.
You mean we're stuck here until morning?
Yeah, the Train of Thought
doesn't run while she's asleep.
- We can't wait that long.
- How about we wake her up?
Sadness, that's ridiculous!
How could we possibly...
How about we wake her up?
- Great idea, Joy.
- Thanks. Come on!
This place is huge!
Yeah, it looks so much smaller
than I expected.
I Can Fly? I love that one!
Rainbow Unicorn! She's right there!
My friend says you're famous.
She wants your autograph.
No, no, Sadness,
don't bother Miss Unicorn, okay?
Sorry, she's from out of town.
That was so embarrassing, right?
I loved you in
Fairy Dream Adventure Part 7.
Okay, bye. I love you!
Wonder what that means.
Well, let's go in.
Set up the classroom set!
Today's memories are in!
We've got a lot to work with here.
Riley dumped her best friend,
had a miserable day at school,
and quit hockey.
The writers have
put together a killer script!
Just because Joy and Sadness are gone,
I have to do stupid Dream Duty.
Okay. How are we going to wake her up?
Well, she wakes up sometimes
when she has a scary dream.
We could scare her.
Scare her? No,
she's been through enough already.
- But, Joy...
- Sadness,
you may know your way
around down here, but I know Riley.
We're gonna make her so happy,
she'll wake up with exhilaration.
We'll excite her awake!
That's never happened before.
Riley loves dogs. Put this on.
I don't think that'll work.
- Bing Bong?
- Yeah?
- Don't let anything happen to these.
- Got it.
Add the reality distortion filter.
Love it. Remember,
play to the camera, everyone!
Riley is the camera!
Makeup, get out of there,
we are on in five, four, three...
Hello, class.
Before we begin today's pop quiz...
Man, she is one bad actress.
...which counts for 90%
of your final grade,
I want to introduce
our new student. Riley.
Would you like to stand up
- and introduce yourself?
- Camera.
And cue Riley.
My name is Riley Andersen.
I'm from Minnesota and now I live here.
Look! Her teeth are falling out!
- That's disgusting.
- Gross!
Teeth falling out.
Yeah, I'm used to that one.
Let me guess, we have no pants on.
Hey, look! She came to school
with no pants on!
Called it!
Ready?
I don't think this happy thing
is going to work. But if we scare her...
Just follow my lead. Here we go.
Bark! Bark! Bark!
Who is that?
What's going on?
You're on! Go!
Let's party! Let's dance!
Hey, a party.
Bark, bark, bark!
Joy, this isn't working.
Sadness, what are you doing?
Come back here!
It's just a dream, it's just a dream.
It's just a dream.
They're trying to wake her up.
Call security!
Hi, Riley, it's me!
- Who's your friend who likes to play?
- Bing Bong?
- Bing Bong, Bing Bong!
- Sadness, stop! It was working!
Sadness! You are ruining this dream!
You're scaring her!
But look, it's working!
They are not part of this dream.
Get them!
Stop right there!
Pan away! Pan away!
Pick a plotline!
- Careful!
- Hold still!
You can't do this!
I know people in Headquarters!
Cut that out! Please!
Do you like candy? You look hungry.
I get you candy! No!
No, no. No, no!
There go the Core Memories!
I can't go in there!
I'm scared of the dark! Please!
Come on.
- What is this place?
- The Subconscious.
It's where they take
all the troublemakers.
My hat feels loose.
How do we get in?
- Let me see.
- You got my hat? Or is that your hat?
- Yeah, it's my hat.
- You sure? Look in the label.
- Yeah, it says, "My hat."
- Wait, it says, "My hat"?
- My hat, it says.
- That's what I wrote in my hat.
- What are you talking about?
- You've got my hat on.
Okay, but it's my handwriting.
- Hey! You!
- You caught us!
Get back in there! No escaping!
I don't like it here. It's where
they keep Riley's darkest fears.
It's broccoli.
The stairs to the basement!
Grandma's vacuum cleaner!
Okay, come on.
- Would you walk quieter?
- I'm trying.
What is going...
Candy wrappers?
- Bing Bong!
- Joy?
There you are.
It's Jangles.
Who's the birthday girl?
Do you have the Core Memories?
Yeah. All he cared about was the candy!
We're out of here!
Let's get to that train!
Wait! The train's not running.
We still have to wake up Riley.
But how?
Oh, no!
Hey, Sadness. Did you hear
about the party they were having?
Yeah. Yes, Joy.
Isn't it a birthday party?
Did you say birthday?
And there's going to be
cake and presents.
And games and balloons...
A birthday?
Okay. Follow us!
Nothing like a good scare
to wake you up, right?
Okay, but it's my handwriting.
No it isn't. That's my... I wrote that.
No, but this one's my handwriting.
Who's the birthday girl?
Come on, let's go!
We made it!
Guess who's on their way
to Headquarters!
We are!
- What is going on?
- He did it again!
We were at school, and we were naked,
and there was a dog,
and his back half was chasing him
and then we saw Bing Bong!
You idiot! It was a dream!
This is ridiculous!
We can't even get
a good night's sleep anymore.
Time to take action.
Stupid Mom and Dad.
If they hadn't moved us,
none of this would've happened.
Who's with me?
No.
Yeah. Let's do it.
She took it. There's no turning back.
So how are we going
to get to Minnesota from here?
Well, why don't we go down
to the elephant lot
and rent an elephant?
Hey. That sounds nice.
We're taking the bus, nitwit!
There's a bus leaving tomorrow. Perfect!
A ticket costs money.
How do we get money?
- Mom's purse.
- You wouldn't.
But I would.
Where was it we saw it last?
- TripleDent gum
- No!
It's downstairs somewhere.
Mom and Dad got us into this mess.
They can pay to get us out.
How about this, huh? Isn't this nice?
You can see everything from up here.
Look, there's Inductive Reasoning.
There's Déja Vu.
There's Language Processing.
There's Critical Thinking.
There's Déja Vu.
Hey, look at this, guys! Memories!
Hey. That was a good idea.
About scaring Riley awake.
You're not so bad.
Really?
Nice work.
I can't wait to get the old Riley back.
As soon as we get there,
I'm going to fix this whole mess.
Is this Riley?
She's so big now.
She won't fit in my rocket.
How are we gonna get to the moon?
It's that time in the twisty tree,
remember?
The hockey team showed up
and Mom and Dad were there cheering.
Look at her, having fun and laughing.
I love this one.
I love that one, too.
Atta girl! Now you're getting it!
Yeah. It was the day the Prairie Dogs
lost the big playoff game.
Riley missed the winning shot.
She felt awful. She wanted to quit.
Sorry. I went sad again, didn't I?
I'll tell you what. We can keep working
on that when we get back. Okay?
Okay.
But I just don't understand.
Why did our moving van even go to Texas?
Multiple customers?
Well, we were promised
delivery on the fifth.
Excuse me, isn't there any way
that you can rush it?
Honesty Island?
Look out!
Come on!
Hold on!
Hurry up! Come on! Over here!
Come on, people! Let's, go, go, go!
Oh that was our way home.
We lost another island?
What is happening?
Haven't you heard? Riley's running away.
What?
Wait, wait, hang on, guys.
Are we really doing this?
I mean, this is serious.
Look. We have no Core Memories.
You want Riley to be happy?
Let's get back to Minnesota
and make more.
Joy, if we hurry, we can still stop her.
Family Island. Let's go!
Joy! Joy! It's too dangerous!
We won't make it in time.
But that's our only way back!
A recall tube!
We can get recalled!
Have a great day, sweetheart.
See you after school, monkey.
We love you!
Go! Run, run! Go!
Whoa! Whoa! Sadness! Sadness, stop!
You're hurting Riley!
No, no, no! I did it again!
If you get in here,
these Core Memories will get sad.
I'm sorry. Riley needs to be happy.
Joy?
Joy!
Joy, what are you doing?
Will you stop it, please?
Don't you get it, Joy?
We're stuck down here.
We're forgotten.
We used to play tag and stuff.
But everything's different now.
Since we moved.
Do you remember how she used to stick
her tongue out when she was coloring?
I could listen to her stories all day.
I just wanted Riley to be happy.
And now...
It was the day the Prairie Dogs
lost the big playoff game.
Riley missed the winning shot.
She felt awful.
She wanted to quit.
Sadness.
Mom and Dad... The team...
They came to help because of Sadness.
We have to get back up there.
Joy, we're stuck down here.
We might as well be on another planet.
Another planet.
Who's your friend who likes to play?
His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"
Who's the best in every way
and wants to sing this song to say?
Who's your friend who likes to play?
Bing Bong, Bing Bong
His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"
Hop in.
Who's your friend who likes to play?
Bing Bong, Bing Bong
His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"
Who's the best in every way
and wants to sing this song to say
Who's your friend who likes to play?
Bing Bong, Bing Bong
His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"
Who's the best in every way
and wants to sing the song to say...
Come on!
Who's your friend who likes to play?
Bing Bong, Bing Bong
His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"
Who's the best in every way
and wants to sing this song to say
Who's your friend who likes to play?
Come on, Joy. One more time.
I got a feeling about this one.
Bing Bong, Bing Bong
His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"
Who's the best in every way
and wants to sing this song to say
Who's your friend who likes to play?
Bing Bong, Bing Bong
Louder! Joy, sing louder!
To sing this song to say
Who's your friend who likes to...
Who's your friend who likes to play?
Bing Bong, Bing Bong
His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"
Who's the best in every way
and wants to sing this song to say
Bing Bong
We're gonna make it!
Bing Bong! We did it!
We... Bing Bong? Bing Bong!
You made it!
Go! Go save Riley!
Take her to the moon for me. Okay?
I'll try, Bing Bong.
I promise.
We're home!
Riley? Riley!
I'll call her cell.
This is terrible. Wait,
is that someone walking towards us?
Yep, let's cross the street.
It's Mom. She's onto us!
- What do we do?
- Where's my bag?
Riley needs to get Core Memories.
- That's the stuff.
- We keep going.
Sadness!
Sadness! Sadness?
Come on, Sadness. Where are you?
Okay. If I were Sadness,
where would I be?
Everything is awful
and my legs don't work,
and you have to drag me around
while I touch all the...
Oh, no! It's Mom again! What do we do?
This is madness! She shouldn't run away!
Let's get this idea out of her head.
Sadness?
- Sadness!
- Joy?
Wait! Sadness!
Just let me go!
Riley's better off without me!
Come back!
Okay, you're saying your husband
was blown away by an elephant.
Was he with anyone?
Yes! And there she is!
Hey! Come back here!
Forget it, Jake. It's Cloud Town.
What? Sadness!
I only make everything worse!
Wait! Sadness!
We got to get you back to...
- It's stuck!
- Great.
- What do you mean it's stuck?
- Now what?
Oh, no! What is this?
- How do we stop it?
- I got it!
Make her feel scared!
That'll make her change her mind!
- Brilliant!
- I know it's brilliant! Do it!
Nothing's working! Why isn't it working?
- Let me try.
- Great! You broke it!
- No, I didn't! Don't touch that!
- Move!
Guys, we can't make Riley feel anything.
What have we done?
Hey! Hey, look at me!
Did you mean what you said before?
I would die for Riley!
Yeah, okay, haircut. Time to prove it.
That's it! I fold!
This is crazy. This is crazy.
No, no, no. Joy. Be positive.
I am positive this is crazy!
- Now!
- For Riley!
- Joy?
- Hang on!
I wish Joy was here!
It's Joy!
Stand back!
That worked.
Well, what would you do,
if you're so smart?
I'd tell you,
but you're too dumb to understand.
What?
Of course your tiny brain is confused.
Guess I'll just have to
dumb it down to your level.
Sorry I don't speak moron
as well as you, but let me try. Duh!
Thank goodness you're back!
- Things are really messed up!
- We found this idea.
We were just
trying to make happy memories.
Joy, you got to fix this! Get up there!
Sadness, it's up to you.
- Me?
- Sadness?
I can't, Joy.
Yes, you can. Riley needs you.
Okay.
Wait! Stop! I want to get off!
All right. Thank you. We will.
Her teacher
hasn't even seen Riley all day.
- What was she wearing last?
- I can't believe this.
Riley, there you are! Thank goodness!
We were worried sick!
Where have you been? It's so late!
Honey! What happened? Are you all right?
We asked the neighbors,
I called the school,
we talked to your teacher.
I know you don't want me to but...
I miss home.
I miss Minnesota.
You need me to be happy, but...
I want my old friends,
and my hockey team.
I want to go home.
Please don't be mad.
- Sweetie.
- We're not mad.
You know what? I miss Minnesota too.
I miss the woods where we took hikes.
And the backyard where you used to play.
Spring Lake, where you learned to skate.
Come here.
Hey, I'm liking this new view.
Friendship Island has expanded.
Glad they finally opened
that Friendly Argument section.
I like Tragic Vampire Romance Island.
Fashion Island? Everyone shut up.
Boy Band Island?
Hope that's just a phase.
Say what you want,
I think it's all beautiful.
All right. Here you go.
Your new expanded console
is up and running.
Cool! Upgrade!
Hey! Whoops, wait. Did I just do that?
Hey, guys? What's pub-er-ty?
I don't know.
It's probably not important.
I have access
to the entire curse word library!
This new console is the...
Sorry. I did it again. My bad.
They're getting to the rink.
Now when you get out there,
you be aggressive!
- I know, Dad.
- But not too aggressive.
You know, you guys don't
have to come to every game.
Are you kidding? I'm not missing one!
Go Foghorns!
- Go Riley! Foghorns are the best!
- Okay! I got to go!
They love us.
Yeah, Mom and Dad are pretty cool.
Guys, of course they are.
But we can't show it.
She loved the face painting!
Told you it was a great idea!
- Best idea he's had in a while.
- He's a really good guy.
Just in case.
Oh! Sorry.
Girl! Girl! Girl!
Okay. Bye.
Remember, just hustle.
- Go, Riley!
- You got this!
- You ready?
- Yeah.
All right. Let's play some hockey!
All right, Anger, take it!
Give us that puck or you're dead meat!
On our left. On our left!
Let's just try
not to get all smelly this time.
Mom and Dad are watching us fail.
Not for long!
We've been through a lot lately,
that's for sure.
But we still love our girl.
She has great new friends,
a great new house.
Things couldn't be better.
After all, Riley's twelve now.
What could happen?
And who can tell me what year
San Francisco was founded?
Anyone? Jordan?
How much more of this?
Five months, two weeks and four days
until summer vacation.
Then it's off to the Bahamas
with you know who!
Come fly with me, gatinha.
Have a nice day.
What are we mad about?
I don't know. Whatever Troy's mad about.
- What's Troy mad about?
- I don't know.
I know. Totally.
We're a total fraud!
Do you think they can see through us?
Of course not! We're wearing eye shadow!
Being cool is so exhausting.
Who's the birthday girl? Hey! Hello!
Six years of drama school for this?
Move it, will you?
What are you doing? Come on!
You know what? This is okay.
This is fine.
We just need to go to our happy place.
TripleDent gum
No! Not this again!